Finding Aid for Michigan Memorial Phoenix Project Records, 1947-2003
Bentley Historical Library
- Director's Topical Files, 1950-1969
  - Reports
    - Health Physics Training, 1958 (Box 17)
    - Initial Calibration of the Ford Nuclear Reactor, 1958 (Box 17)
    - Laboratory Operations, 1962 (Box 17)
    - Leukemia Research, 195? (Box 17)
    - Low Enrichment Fuel, undated (Box 17)
    - Need for Safety Policy in Atoms for Peace Program, Whipple, Kerr, and Simon, 1961 (Box 17)
    - Phoenix Project: A Continuing Investigation into Peacetime Implications and Applications of Atomic Energy, circa 1959 (Box 17)
    - Plutonium Research, 1958 (Box 17)
    - Progress, 1951 (Box 17)
    - Quarterly Reports, 1957-1963 (Box 17)
    - Regulating the Uses of Ionizing Radiations, 1961 (Box 17)
    - Reports to the President, 1961-1963 (Box 17)
    - Research Institute, 1953-1955 (Box 17)
    - Status Reports, 1959-1960 (Box 17)
  - Reports
    - Uses of Upjohn Co. Gift, undated (Box 17)
    - Utilization Reports, 1957-1961 (Box 17)
    - Vilella's Use of Ionizing Radiation on Parasitic Diseases, 1959 (Box 17)
  - Research Account, General, 1951-1959 (Box 17)
  - Roberts, Robert, 1959-1960 (Box 17)
  - Robinson, Irwin J., 1960 (Box 17)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1961 (Box 17)
  - Rohl, Benjamin, 1959-1960 (Box 17)
  - Ruthven, Alexander, 1959-1961 (Box 17)
  - Sackett, Samuel, 1959-1960 (Box 17)
  - Sawyer, Dean Ralph, 1959-1960 (Box 17)
  - Sawyer, R.N., 1959-1960 (Box 17)
  - Seabury, Charles, 1959-1960 (Box 17)
  - Space and Space Planning (includes blueline prints), 1952-1960 (Box 17)
  - Speeches, Speech Material, Scripts
    - General, 1950s (Box 17)
    - Gomberg and Sawyer, 1950-1958 (Box 17)
    - Leatherman, 1956-1960; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Summer School, 1952 (Box 17)
  - Telecourse, 1954-1955 (Box 17)
  - Thompson, Paul, 1960 (Box 17)
  - Tour of Phoenix Memorial Lab and Ford Nuclear Reactor, undated (Box 17)
  - Use of Facilities, 1955-1958 (Box 17)
  - Visitors, 1959 (Box 18)
  - Vogt, Frederic, 1959-1960 (Box 18)
  - Watkins, James, 1958-1961 (Box 18)
  - Whipple, G. Hoyt, 1957-1964 (Box 18)
  - Wickes, Randall, 1959-1960 (Box 18)
  - Zeder, James (includes photograph), 1959-1960 (Box 18)
- Ford Reactor
  The Ford Reactor series, 1951-1970 (1.5 linear ft.), was primarily generated from the office of W.R. Dunbar while he served as reactor supervisor. Material in the series includes correspondence with director William Kerr and general correspondence relating to reactor operations. There are also operations summaries, operator training materials, reports, and notes. Operations summaries delineate the number of hours the reactor operated at various powers and the extent to which work was oriented toward teaching or toward research. The series includes a survey designed by Dunbar in 1964 to identify and describe educational, research, and industrial nuclear reactors in existence at the time in the United States. Construction related documents are also contained in the files.
  - Control System for Nuclear Research Reactor, 1951-1956 (Box 18)
  - Collected Material and Notes (Dunbar), 4 folders (Box 18)
  - Correspondence
    - Dunbar, 1960-1966 (Box 18)
    - Dunbar and Kerr, 1959-1968 (Box 18)
    - With Reactor Specifications (construction related), 1952-1954 (Box 18)
    - Description and operation, 1957 (Box 54)
  - Description and Operation, 1962 (Box 18)
  - Diagrams, 1962 (Box 18)
  - Dunbar Reference Papers and Notes, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Dunbar Nuclear Plant Survey and Notes, circa 1964 (Box 18)
  - Gamma Analyzer, 1962 (Box 18)
  - Library, Bibliography, 1967 (Box 18)
  - Operations Summaries, 1958-1970; 3 folders (Box 19)
  - Operator Training, 1963-1966; 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Personnel, Lab Watchman, 1962 (Box 19)
  - Reports
    - Conversion, 1962 (Box 19)
    - Radiation Control Services, 1959-1969 (Box 19)
    - And untitled, Undated (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous Reactor Files (Box 19)
- Organizations
  The Organizations series, 1955-1967 (5 linear ft.), is a valuable source for understanding the extent to which the influence of the Phoenix Project extended well beyond Michigan. The bulk of the material relates to the relationship of Phoenix personnel with the International Cooperation Agency (ICA), an arm of the Atomic Energy Commission (AEC). Phoenix scientists provided consulting services, which included advising ICA Washington and conducting missions in the field in connection with the U.S. Atoms for Peace Program. Working closely with scientific and educational personnel in numerous countries, Gomberg, Kerr, Sawyer and others evaluated research proposals, reviewed the design of laboratories, advised on the selection of equipment, and participated in the planning of educational programs. ICA files include briefings, correspondence, itineraries, background papers, and some technical reports. The Visit Reports subseries is comprised of the more formal reports written for the ICA Nuclear Energy Program. These documents include evaluations of programs, comments, recommendations, lists of participants, resources, and sometimes photocopied photographs. There are also records relating to the Argonne National Laboratory, the Associated Midwest Universities Nuclear Engineering Evaluation Committee, and the American Nuclear Society. It is of value to note that there are additional records relating to the involvement of Phoenix staff in various organizations in the Director's Topical Files series.
  - Advisory Committee for Isotopes and Radiation Development, 1959-1961; 6 folders (Box 20)
  - American Nuclear Society, 1958-1961 (Box 20)
  - Argonne National Laboratory (ANL)
    - Correspondence, 1955-1959 (Box 20)
    - Educational Affairs Committee, 1963-1967; 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Associated Midwest Universities (AMU) Nuclear Engineering Evaluation Committee, 1960-1961; 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Associated Midwest Universities (AMU) Nuclear Engineering Evaluation Committee, 1962-1965; 3 folders (Box 21)
  - Atomic Industrial Forum, 1958-1960 (Box 21)
  - Atomic Power Development Assn., 1955-1961 (Box 21)
  - Institute of Science and Engineering, 1960 (Box 21)
  - International Cooperation Administration (ICA)
    - Administration, 1956-1964; 5 folders (Box 21)
      (see also Contracts and Correspondence)
    - Argentina, 1961 (Box 22)
    - Asia Foundation, 1959 (Box 22)
    - Asian Nuclear Center, 1956-1957 (Box 22)
    - Baghdad, 1957 (Box 22)
    - Bolivian Erythrocythemia study -- A Critical Review by C.S. Simons, 1964 (Box 22)
    - Brazil, 1958-1960 (Box 22)
    - Budgets, 1958-1964 (Box 22)
    - Columbia, 1957-1958 (Box 22)
    - Contracts, 1956-1965 (Box 22)
    - Correspondence, William Kerr, 1957-1959 (Box 22)
    - Dacca, University of, undated (Box 22)
    - Ecuador, 1957-1961 (Box 22)
    - El Salvador, 1960-1962 (Box 22)
    - General (includes final report, 1965), 1957-1965 (Box 22)
    - Germany, 1957 (Box 22)
    - Greece, 1959-1960 (Box 22)
    - Hayodom, Vichai, 1957-1960 (Box 22)
    - Ice, 1959 (Box 22)
    - Indonesia, 1956-1960 (Box 22)
    - Indonesian Radioisotope Lab, 1960 (Box 22)
    - Ionizing Radiation Protection Meeting, 1961 (Box 22)
    - Iran, 1957-1960 (Box 22)
    - Iraq, 1959 (Box 22)
    - Israel, 1959-1962 (Box 22)
    - Japan, 1958-1961 (Box 22)
    - Jordan, 1960 (Box 22)
    - Korea, 1958-1959 (Box 22)
    - Lebanon, 1957-1961 (Box 22)
    - Nicaragua, 1961 (Box 22)
    - Pakistan, 1957-1965; 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Panama, 1961-1962 (Box 23)
    - Peru, 1960 (Box 23)
    - Philippines, 1959-1961 (Box 23)
    - Project Progress Reports, 1957-1963 (Box 23)
    - Puerto Rico, 1958 (Box 23)
    - Salary and Security Clearances, 1957-1960 (Box 23)
    - Simonds, Charles, 1958-1964 (Box 23)
    - South Africa, 1961 (Box 23)
    - South Vietnam, 1961 (Box 23)
    - Spain, 1959-1961 (Box 23)
    - Radiation in Control of Insect Pests, 1960 (Box 23)
    - Taiwan, 1957-1963; 2 folders
      - General, 1957-1963; 2 folders (Box 23)
      - Academia Sinica, 1959 (Box 23)
      - Chung Kung University, 1959 (Box 23)
      - National Taiwan University, 1959-1960 (Box 23)
      - Nuclear Energy Training, 1959 (Box 23)
      - Tsing Hua University, 1959-1962 (Box 23)
    - Thailand
      - General, 1957-1961 (Box 23)
      - Atomic Energy Commission, 1959-1961 (Box 23)
      - Education Program, 1957-1959 (Box 23)
      - Equipment Lists, 1956-1960 (Box 23)
      - Reactor Training Program, 1956-1957 (Box 23)
    - Tunisia, 1958-1959 (Box 23)
    - Turkey, 1957-1962 (Box 23)
    - Visit Reports
      - Belgian Congo, C.S. Simons, June 1960 (Box 24)
      - Baghdad Report, Beierwaltes, October 1963 (Box 24)
      - Bolivia Report, C.S. Simons, April 1963 (Box 24)
      - Central America, Kerr and Emmonds, 1961; 1963 (Box 24)
      - Columbia Report, No. 1, H. J. Gomberg, February 1958 (Box 24)
      - Ecuador Report, No. 1, H. J. Gomberg, April 1958 (Box 24)
      - Ecuador Report, No. 2, W. W. Meinke, June 1961 (Box 24)
      - Formosa Report, No. 1, W. Kerr & R. A. Sawyer, May 1959 (Box 24)
      - Formosa Report No. 2, H. Frank, October 1959 (Box 24)
      - Formosa Report No. 3, W. Kerr & K. H. Sun, December 1960 (Box 24)
      - Formosa Report, No. 4, K. H. Sun (Tsing Hua), October 1961 (Box 24)
      - Formosa Report, W. W. Meinke, 1962 (Box 24)
      - Greece Report, No. 1, H. J. Gomberg, April 1959 (Box 24)
      - Greece Report, No. 2, H. J. Gomberg, December 1959 (Box 24)
      - Greece Report, No. 3, H. J. Gomberg, May 1961 (Box 24)
      - Indian Report, G. H. Whipple, December 1964 (Box 24)
      - International Atomic Energy, W. J. Gomberg, December 1959 (Box 24)
      - Indonesia Report, Simons & Brownell, August 1958 (Box 24)
      - Israel Report, No. 1, G. H. Whipple, March 1960 (Box 24)
      - Israel Report, No. 2, H. J. Gomberg, May 1961 (Box 24)
      - Iran Report, G. H. Whipple, November 1957 (Box 24)
      - Iraq Report, No. 1, W. Kerr, October 1957 (Box 24)
      - Japan and Korea, H. J. Gomberg, January 1959 (Box 24)
      - Korea Report, G. H. Whipple, April 1958 (Box 24)
      - Korea, Nuclear Power for, Whipple & Kerr, May 1960 (Box 24)
      - Korea Report, W. Meinke, April 1962 (Box 24)
      - Lebanon Report 1, W. Kerr, May 1957 (Box 24)
      - Pakistan Report, No. 1, W. Kerr & G. H. Whipple, October 1957 (Box 24)
      - Pakistan Report, No. 2, W. W. Meinke, December 1959 (Box 24)
      - Pakistan Report, No. 3, G. H. Whipple, October 1961 (Box 24)
      - Pakistan Debriefing, W. Cassatt, September, 1961 (Box 24)
      - Puerto Rico, G. H. Whipple, June 1958 (Box 24)
      - Philippine Report, No. 1, W. Kerr, June 1959 (Box 24)
      - Taiwan, Sawyer & Kerr, May 1959 (Box 24)
      - Taiwan, Kerr & Sun, December 1960 (Box 24)
      - Thailand, W. Kerr, April 1957 (Box 24)
      - Thailand, Meinke, January 1961; December 1962 (Box 24)
      - Tunisia, C.S. Simons, 1958 (Box 24)
      - Turkey, W. Kerr, 1957 (Box 24)
      - Turkey, H.J. Gomberg, 1961 (Box 24)
      - Turkey, Simons, March, 1959 (Box 24)
      - Viet Nam, W.W. Meinke, May 1962 (Box 24)
      - Yugoslavia, August, 1960 (Box 24)
      - Yugoslavia, G.H. Whipple, December, 1958 (Box 24)
      - Yugoslavia, 1957-1962 (Box 24)
      - Washington, 1957-1965; 4 folders (Box 24)
      - Washington, Meem, 1961 (Box 24)
- Prospects
  The Prospects series, 1947-1985 (3 linear ft.), is primarily a set of small files holding correspondence sent to or received from corporations and businesses during the course of fund-raising. Custom printed folders in this series include space for data to be entered about a company, such as location, products, university contacts, officers, and donations. Unfortunately, in many cases the forms in the folders were only slightly utilized. Nevertheless, the series provides an overview of the comprehensive character of the campaign in the corporate realm. Individuals listed in the series usually had a commercial connection or were associated with a foundation.
  - Abbott Laboratories, 1951-1963 (Box 25)
  - American Box Board Company Foundation, 1951-1954 (Box 25)
  - American Cancer Society, 1959-1960 (Box 25)
  - American Motors, 1952-1964 (Box 25)
  - Anderson-Bolling Manufacturing Company, 1952 (Box 25)
  - Bendix Corporation, 1953-1960 (Box 25)
  - Bohn Aluminum & Brass Corporation, 1953-1960 (Box 25)
  - Borg-Warner Foundation, 1953-1961 (Box 25)
  - Briggs Manufacturing Company, 1951-1952 (Box 25)
  - Brown, J.L. Jr., 1961-1962 (Box 25)
  - Bryant & Detwiler, 1951-1961 (Box 25)
  - Buchanan Steel Products Company, 1952-1960 (Box 25)
  - Budd Company, 1960 (Box 25)
  - Buhr Machine Tool Co., 1951 (Box 25)
  - Bulldog Electric Products Company, 1951-1953 (Box 25)
  - Bundy Tubing Company, 1951-1960 (Box 25)
  - Burroughs Adding Machine Company, 1951-1966 (Box 25)
  - Bushnell, Mrs. Miller, 1960 (Box 25)
  - Cadillac-Soo Lumber, 1956 (Box 25)
  - Calumet and Hecla, Inc., 1951-1961 (Box 25)
  - Campbell, Wyant and Cannon Foundry Company, 1952-1954 (Box 25)
  - Central Paper Company, 1951-1954 (Box 25)
  - Champion Spark Plug Company, 1951-1964 (Box 25)
  - Chelsea Milling Company, 1960 (Box 25)
  - Chrysler Corporation, 1951-1964 (Box 25)
  - Clark Equipment Company, 1950-1967 (Box 25)
  - Commercial Steel Treating Corporation, 1960 (Box 25)
  - Commonwealth Associates, 1958-1964 (Box 25)
  - Consumers Power Company, 1950-1965 (Box 25)
  - Continental Motors Corporation, 1952-1959 (Box 25)
  - Crawford, William B., 1960-1964 (Box 25)
  - Cress, Earl H., 1959-1965 (Box 25)
  - Cunningham Drug Stores, undated (Box 25)
  - Dearborn Motors Corporation, undated (Box 25)
  - DeFord, Sara, 1961-1979 (Box 25)
  - Detrex Chemical Industries, Inc., 1961-1964 (Box 25)
  - Detroit Ball Bearing Foundation of Michigan, 1959-1962 (Box 25)
  - Detroit Bank, 1951-1964 (Box 25)
  - Detroit Broach Company, 1952 (Box 25)
  - Detroit Edison Company, 1950-1971 (Box 25)
  - Detroit Gasket and Manufacturing Company, 1951-1960 (Box 25)
  - Detroit Harvester Company, 1952-1956 (Box 25)
  - Detroit Stamping Company, 1951-1960 (Box 25)
  - Detroit Steel Corporation, 1951-1960 (Box 25)
  - Detroit Sulphite Pulp & Paper Company, 1951 (Box 25)
  - Detroit Trust Company, 1951-1955 (Box 25)
  - DeWaters, Enos, 1949-1963 (Box 25)
  - Dow Chemical Company, 1951-1974 (Box 25)
  - Dow, Alden B., 1961-1963 (Box 25)
  - Dow, Herbert & Grace, 1959 (Box 25)
  - Durametallic Corporation, 1952-1968 (Box 25)
  - Eaton Manufacturing Company, Spring Division, 1959 (Box 25)
  - Essex Wire Corporation, 1952-1960 (Box 25)
  - Evans Winter Hebb Incorporated, 1951 (Box 25)
  - Ex-Cell-O Corporation, 1953-1963 (Box 25)
  - "F" Miscellaneous, 1964-1971 (Box 25)
  - Fabricon Products, Inc., 1951 (Box 25)
  - Fairman, James F., 1960 (Box 25)
  - Favrot, Laurence H., 1960 (Box 25)
  - Fead, F. Bingham, 1960 (Box 25)
  - Federal Mogul corporation, 1952-1960 (Box 25)
  - Ferris Memorial Fund (cancer research), 1962-1963 (Box 25)
  - Ferro Stamping Company, 1951 (Box 25)
  - Ferry Foundation, 1960 (Box 25)
  - Field Foundation, Inc., 1960 (Box 25)
  - Fingerle, Phyllis, 1961 (Box 25)
  - Fink, George R. and Elise, 1960 (Box 25)
  - Firestone Tire & Rubber, undated (Box 25)
  - Firnschild memorial Fund (basic cancer research), 1962 (Box 25)
  - Fisher, Max M., 1960-1961 (Box 25)
  - Fitzsimons Manufacturing company, 1951 (Box 25)
  - Foote, J.H., 1959 (Box 25)
  - Ford Motor Company, 1952-1980; 4 folders (Box 25)
  - Foster, Ruth and Dietz, Ada, 1963-1972 (Box 25)
  - Fralick, Dr.& Mrs. Bruce, 1960 (Box 25)
  - Fram Corporation, 1950-1960 (Box 25)
  - Frauenthal, A.H., 1959-1966 (Box 25)
  - French, Dean David, 1959-1960 (Box 25)
  - Friedman, Louis K., 1961-1962 (Box 25)
  - Fruehauf Trailer Company, 1951-1953 (Box 25)
  - Furstenberg, Dr. Albert C., 1960 (Box 25)
  - "G" Miscellaneous, 1966-1972 (Box 25)
  - Gannett, Joseph, 1960-1961 (Box 25)
  - Gardner, Marion L., 1960-1974 (Box 25)
  - Gardner, Jack R., 1961 (Box 25)
  - Gaskin, Mervyn Foundation, Inc., 1960-1961 (Box 25)
  - Gault, Harry, 1959-1964 (Box 25)
  - Genebach, Lowell B., 1959-1960 (Box 25)
  - General Electric Company, 1950-1968 (Box 25)
  - General Motors Company (includes photograph), 1950-1964 (Box 25)
  - George Foundation, The Edwin S., 1959-1960 (Box 25)
  - Gerber Products Company, 1952-1969 (Box 25)
  - Gerstacker, Carl A., 1959-1964 (Box 25)
  - Gilmore, Donald S., 1960 (Box 25)
  - Goebel Brewing Company, 1960 (Box 25)
  - Gomberg, Dr. Henry J., 1961 (Box 25)
  - Goodyear, 1951-1975 (Box 25)
  - Gordon, John F., 1959 (Box 25)
  - Graham, Ford M., 1960 (Box 25)
  - Grand Rapids Foundation, 1959-1960 (Box 25)
  - Great Lakes Steel Corporation, 1951-1964 (Box 25)
  - Grebinar, Mrs. H.L. (Edith), 1959 (Box 25)
  - Green, Dr. Lewis, 1960 (Box 25)
  - Gregory, George E., 1960-1963 (Box 26)
  - Griffen, Glenn H., 1961-1962 (Box 26)
  - Gulf, 1960 (Box 26)
  - Gustine, A. Neil, 1960 (Box 26)
  - "H" Miscellaneous, 1960-1975 (Box 26)
  - Hafstad, Dr. Lawrence R., 1959-1962 (Box 26)
  - Haiduck, Andrew F., 1960 (Box 26)
  - Hale, Clayton G., 1960 (Box 26)
  - Hammond, Robert S., 1959 (Box 26)
  - Hancock Manufacturing Company, 1951-1953 (Box 26)
  - Hancock, John C., 1959 (Box 26)
  - Harder Foundation, 1959-1972 (Box 26)
  - Hartley, Mrs. Harold, 1960 (Box 26)
  - Hasselbach, William H., 1960-1963 (Box 26)
  - Hastings Manufacturing Company, 1951 (Box 26)
  - Hayes Industries Incorporated, 1951-1963 (Box 26)
  - Hazen, Ronald M., 1960 (Box 26)
  - Heath, Milton W., 1960-1963 (Box 26)
  - Hess, Robert, 1962 (Box 26)
  - Hill, G. Carlton, 1959-1960 (Box 26)
  - Hillery, Verne, 1959 (Box 26)
  - Hodges, Dr., 1961-1977 (Box 26)
  - Holmes, Henry, 1960 (Box 26)
  - Hoobler, Sibley, 1960 (Box 26)
  - Hoover Ball and Bearing Company, 1950 (Box 26)
  - Hoover, H. Earl, 1961-1985 (Box 26)
  - Hough, William, 1960-1962 (Box 26)
  - Hudson, J.L. Company, 1951-1960; 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Hudson, J.L., Jr., 1959 (Box 26)
  - Hudson Motor Car Company, 1954-1955 (Box 26)
  - Hughes, Clair B., 1959-1963 (Box 26)
  - Hughes, Howard, 1960 (Box 26)
  - "I" Miscellaneous, 1960-1975 (Box 26)
  - Icerman, Paul F., 1961-1962 (Box 26)
  - Industrial Brownhoist Corporation, 1951-1952 (Box 26)
  - Industrial Stamping and Manufacturing Company, 1951 (Box 26)
  - Institute of Industrial Health, 1965 (Box 26)
  - Ishpeming Cancer Society, 1960-1964 (Box 26)
  - "J" Miscellaneous, 1967-1971 (Box 26)
  - Jacobs, F.L. Company, 1953-1956 (Box 26)
  - Jacobson Stores, 1960 (Box 26)
  - James Foundation, 1960 (Box 26)
  - Jaquillard, George E., 1960-1962 (Box 26)
  - Jarecki Corp., 1953-1959 (Box 26)
  - Jensen Foundation, 1960-1964 (Box 26)
  - Jervis Corporation, 1951 (Box 26)
  - Johnson, E.R., 1959-1961 (Box 26)
  - "K" Miscellaneous, 1960-1962 (Box 26)
  - Kalamazoo Vegetable Parchment Company, 1952-1959 (Box 26)
  - Kanzler, Leopold, 1961-1964 (Box 26)
  - Kanzler, Ernest C., 1959-1960 (Box 26)
  - Kaydon Engineering Corporation, 1952-1959 (Box 26)
  - Keeler Brass Company, 1959-1979 (Box 26)
  - Keeler, M.S. II, 1959-1979 (Box 26)
  - Keeler, Paul L., 1962 (Box 26)
  - Kelsey Hayes Wheel Company, 1951-1959 (Box 26)
  - King Seeley Corporation, 1952-1960 (Box 26)
  - King, Jane Gunderman, 1959 (Box 26)
  - King, Lawrence S., 1959 (Box 26)
  - King, Mrs. J. Stanley, 1959 (Box 26)
  - Kipke, Henry G., 1959 (Box 26)
  - Kirby, Hilda, 1959-1964 (Box 26)
  - Kirkbride, C.G., 1959-1960 (Box 26)
  - Knape and Vogt Mfg., 1959 (Box 26)
  - Kresge Foundation, 1959-1975 (Box 26)
  - Kucher, Dr. Andrew, 1959-1975 (Box 26)
  - "L" Miscellaneous, 1960-1971 (Box 26)
  - Lamsam, Bancha, 1963-1967 (Box 26)
  - Landers Foundation, 1960-1964 (Box 26)
  - Lang, Chester H., 1959-1960 (Box 26)
  - Lathrop Company, 1960-1961 (Box 26)
  - Lawton, J. Fred,1959 (Box 26)
  - Leader, Dr. Luther, 1959-1960 (Box 26)
  - Lear Foundation, 1960 (Box 26)
  - Leeds & Northrop Company, 1960-1961 (Box 26)
  - Leonard Refineries, Inc., 1951-1961 (Box 26)
  - Letchfield, Dr. Francis H., 1959-1964 (Box 26)
  - Levinson, Ben, 1959-1960 (Box 26)
  - Libbey-Owens-Ford Glass Co., 1950-1966 (Box 26)
  - Lilly Endowment Inc., 1959-1961 (Box 26)
  - Lilly, Eli & Co., 1951-1961 (Box 26)
  - Litton Industries, Inc., 1959 (Box 26)
  - Lloyd, Alice, 1960-1961 (Box 26)
  - Loose, Harold G., 1919 (Box 26)
  - Lorillard (P.) Company, 1951-1952 (Box 26)
  - Loutit, William R., 1959-1962 (Box 26)
  - Ludwig, Dr. Frederick E., 1959-1964 (Box 26)
  - Lundberg, Nils A., 1960-1963 (Box 26)
  - Lyon, Inc., 1950-1967 (Box 26)
  - "M" Miscellaneous, 1960-1971 (Box 26)
  - MacLaughlin, Earle, 1959-1960 (Box 26)
  - Madigan, Edward P., 1959-1963 (Box 26)
  - Mahon, R.C. Company, 1960 (Box 26)
  - Manufacturer's National Bank of Detroit, 1951-1959 (Box 26)
  - Marathon Linen Service, Inc., 1959 (Box 26)
  - Marble, J.D., 1961-1965 (Box 26)
  - Marion Agency, 1959-1960 (Box 26)
  - Martens, Harry M., 1960-1964 (Box 26)
  - Mason, George, 1981 (Box 26)
  - Matthaei, Frederick C., Jr., 1959-1963 (Box 26)
  - "Mc" Miscellaneous, 1961-1971 (Box 26)
  - McCabe, James W., 1960-1971 (Box 26)
  - McCarthy, T.J. Steamship Co., 1959 (Box 26)
  - McCarty, John T., 1959 (Box 26)
  - McCord Corporation, 1952-1959 (Box 26)
  - McGregor Fund, 1960-1964 (Box 26)
  - McInerney Spring & Wire Company, 1953-1963 (Box 26)
  - McIntyre, Brouwer, 1960-1964 (Box 26)
  - McIntyre, Charles S., 1960-1964 (Box 26)
  - McIntyre, William D., 1960-1964 (Box 26)
  - McLouth Steel Corporation, 1952-1960 (Box 26)
  - McPhee, Ar, 1959-1962 (Box 26)
  - Mead Corporation, 1960-1962
  - Mechanical Handling systems Inc., 1951 (Box 26)
  - Meinke, Dr. Wayne, 1961-1968 (Box 26)
  - Merker, Dr. Harvey M., 1959 (Box 26)
  - Mersereau, Howard J., 1959-1962 (Box 26)
  - Metal Office Furniture Company, 1950-1953 (Box 26)
  - Meyer, Fred, 1961 (Box 26)
  - Michigan Bell Telephone, 1951-1964 (Box 26)
  - Michigan Consolidated Gas Company, 1950-1964 (Box 26)
  - Michigan Dept. of Economic Development, 1961 (Box 26)
  - Michigan Fruit Canners Inc., 1960 (Box 26)
  - Michigan National Bank, 1952-1960 (Box 26)
  - Michigan Seamless Tube Company, 1952-1953 (Box 26)
  - Miel, Lucas S., 1959-1964 (Box 26)
  - Miles Laboratories, Inc., 1951-1953 (Box 26)
  - Miller, Stanley, 1960 (Box 26)
  - Miner, Mrs. F. Bishop, 1959 (Box 26)
  - Miscellaneous, 1961-1963 (Box 26)
  - Monroe Auto Equipment Company, 1951-1966 (Box 26)
  - Monroe Calculating Machine Company, 1951-1959 (Box 26)
  - Monroe Manufacturing Company, 1952 (Box 26)
  - Monroe, George, 1959-1963 (Box 26)
  - Monsanto Chemical Company, 1951-1954 (Box 26)
  - Moore, Neil A., 1959-1984 (Box 26)
  - Motor Products Corp., 1951-1952 (Box 26)
  - Motor Wheel Corp., 1959-1960 (Box 26)
  - Mott, Charles Stewart Foundation, 1960-1962 (Box 26)
  - Muehlig, Inc., 1960-1964 (Box 26)
  - Mueller Brass Company, 1960 (Box 26)
  - Muskegon Bank & Trust Company, 1960-1963 (Box 26)
  - "N" Miscellaneous, 1961-1971 (Box 26)
  - National Bank and Trust, 1960-1964 (Box 26)
  - National Bank of Detroit, 1952-1963 (Box 26)
  - National Bank of Jackson, 1960-1964 (Box 26)
  - National Building Corporation, 1950 (Box 26)
  - Newman, James B., 1968-1989 (Box 26)
  - "O" Miscellaneous, 1967-1968 (Box 27)
  - Ohio Citizens Trust, 1960-1964 (Box 27)
  - Old Kent Bank & Trust, 1960 (Box 27)
  - Ottaway, Dr. John P., 1960 (Box 27)
  - Otto, Frederick A. (Insurance policy), 1969 (Box 27)
  - Owen, Allen, 1960-1964 (Box 27)
  - Owens Corning Fiberglass Corp., 1950-1966 (Box 27)
  - Oyler, Thomas T., 1959-1963 (Box 27)
  - "P" Miscellaneous, 1960-1977 (Box 27)
  - Packaging Corporation of America, 1958-1959 (Box 27)
  - Palmer, Archie, 1962 (Box 27)
  - Palmer, H. Bruce, 1959-1960 (Box 27)
  - Pangborn, Mrs. Lynn, 1960 (Box 27)
  - Paper, Meyer, 1960-1962 (Box 27)
  - Parfet, Ray T., 1961 (Box 27)
  - Parfet, Ray T. Jr., 1960-1961 (Box 27)
  - Parke Davis and Company, 1954-1963 (Box 27)